hi all good evening guys am I audible and visible if you can hear me out can you give
it a thumbs up yeah great guys thank you so let me do the screen share
I know what topics for upcoming context will be yeah I'll come to that
so guys let me know if my screen share is also working fine okay so great so one small
announcement is that this weekend we won't have any class and you will be having the
contest on 24th and 25th Jan right two days of the weekend you can leverage it to attempt it and
this will be based on completely Dom plus HTML plus CSS till Dom part okay and it will also
include the bonds and throttling concept till last class the object oriented programming that
will start today will not be involved in it so I hope you are able you will be able to do it and
be prepared with this guys I think Dom is something you might be experienced with it like we have done
good enough project and you know machine coding and things so you know be prepared with these
two concepts also understand them maybe build your own example try to learn it is this clear
Kabir do you get the contest of like what will be asked in okay great so I hope everyone is
preparing eyes for the contest can we use our own data for solving questions in the contest
you should be able to I'm not exactly sure here as I have to you know I have to check on that how
does it work okay so firstly I'm not sure exactly whether it will be MCQ based it will be having
again machine coding around so and there might be a question where you have to code it down so
three things can be possibilities yeah but we have to submit there only yeah so you know if
it is of and machine coding around the questions will be have simple and straightforward it know
it wouldn't be that big because you have one one hour of context contest and you have to we have
to test you on base of three three knowledge right so if you think from that perspective
mostly it won't be there but you will be having a code and MCQ you have an MCQ mock interview
on Saturday also so can we take it on Sunday no you have two days right contest will be on
two days is it a flag should not be you know writing HTML will be same way right there
shouldn't be any plagiarism issues there okay if you face any of those challenges to let me know
we'll check with the team okay if you are able to execute all the test cases that's that's fine
like that's it that is what main discussion would be it wouldn't be like we are checking
plagiarism although all those things will not be considered right so you just have to execute the
test cases even you will be discussing right I think in HLD sessions where you will be
discussing how actually submission of this questions in contest happens like how what is
the workflow how they test all those you know test cases right like when you would submit your
question there are like 100 or 120 test cases runs simultaneously and you error is in populated
those things happen so fast you will be able to see like how they're working so it's not a
distributed system that of that scale but the processing is the mathematical computation is
heavy okay so we'll get to learn that also okay guys can anyone drop a message in chat
okay okay great some it will use it that thing itself so somebody has built another application
so let me bookmark this one also if you want me to use it for our whole batch
let me see great I have this okay this is a stopwatch I don't have a timer right how
many minutes timer I have to do or build this one some bit so you played around with the box
shadow where you are toggling the colors for each second each time the box had is changing
you have four types of classes flip being played around running through the loop is it
for each second you are having the inner text yeah you set interval and then you
are checking and updating the color right great good idea so I believe like somebody
has applied the same knowledge that we have all just learned it's really great that you
are applying in terms of project because this is where you get on add-on right that you are
learning a concept then you are applying back so from I think somebody are very much clear
with the dom right by now like dom and all those parts but good one good one some would
keep doing keep building good projects for us so I'll reset it I'll set for two minutes
guys then we'll get started but meanwhile anyone having any doubts from the last class
because we have you know picked up bit heavy heavy things like firstly we clear set timeout
then we understood set interval then we went on to understand debouncing then we understood
these are the four concepts we picked it up we used same sort of example as input search
okay but there are many other examples where you can use trottling that I have also given you
examples but hope you try it out and build it out guys you can expect at least one one question
on each of this in the contest so what I have done it for you guys is that as I promised in
last class that I will give you a screenshot where you know you directly see differentiation
and the kit of repo so I'll push this image where you can see that what is the purpose when to use
the bouncing when to use our trottling and what are the different parameters and the examples
events where you can build it okay I hope this thing also helps guys sort of a notes where you
get overview of debouncing and trottling okay so other than this thing guys is everything clear
so just want to know give me thumbs up if you are confident with HTML CSS and DOM operations
and beginning level of JS 2 because we are getting started with new part of JS I just
want to know how confident you are feeling so I see five thumbs up guys is there anyone who's
facing still challenge with the topics that we have learned or if there is anyone who feels like
he's feeling lack you know lacking behind if there is anyone give me thumbs down maybe if we can have
a conversation in the doubt session there is anyone give me thumbs down this because the things we
have covered are all basics are done now from the last class I say to people hey monkey and promote
guys waiting down session will have a conversation will discuss your point of view right so because
you from today on will be moving bit forward and fast so that you don't feel lacking behind okay
and then we'll pick it up so great I don't see people coming up we are 10 minutes of the start
so let's do one thing we'll start with today's class guys so today let's let me start agenda
discussion firstly you know we have three classes for oops and the topics will be covering inside
oops this keyword will understand what is this keyword in context of JavaScript then
we'll understand constructor function okay then we'll understand classes in JS and inheritance
once we cover this then we have I'll talk about that prototype and prototypical inheritance
then we'll have call apply bind methods and we'll understand again in depth again memory of objects
because you know object oriented again it's everything is about objects so we'll come to
them so these are the broader six level topics will be picking up so this will both will go
for first class and then we'll pick it up again these two items in second class then we have third
class for this one okay so these are the topics that will be picking up so firstly we understood
that you know JS is functional programming based language but why did oops coming to the picture
right how many of you understand what oops is firstly how many of you understand what oops is
if there is anyone who don't understand oops okay I see three people cool so object oriented
program so in object oriented programming we'll see of this examples when you come to something
called as constructor function in depth but you know everything revolves around objects
just let's keep this no lighter definition for now but we'll come to the depth understanding oops
and its principles you know object oriented programming is a one of the one of the best
oldest fashion that people have leveraged to build applications because using this thing
they are more able to relate with the real world I'll show you this one
how how they how we are able to relate and what things have all those things are ever
will come to that step by step but before that we have to start one of the topic
understand one of the concept of JS itself like have you heard keyword called use strict in JS
guys have you heard this keyword use strict
I see five people yeah great many people didn't hear it off okay and so what happens is right
yeah bishak rightly pointed out but let's come back to this use strict okay firstly when we
introduce JavaScript we all know that JS comes with a many you know errors or many
functional issues because that was developed in 10 days right and then there was a ECMA team
who kept on improving the JS to write better JavaScript this is something we know the story
right we know what happened and why this happened and how it was JavaScript was developed and there
was too many issues like if you remember we had issues like hosting right that was fixed again
using let and const I mean let and const are still hosted but they are hosted in temporal red zone
right so similarly we had many things right many issues that were there in JS like when it's when
you go for initial JS you had a var keyword which was a global variable all the time and
we had also seen potential issues with a var keyword right all those things were part of the
initial JS issues now also initial JS was not you know throwing us the good required amount of errors
like if you see there are many parts of the code which is not expected to write such way but people
were writing it and that code was being passed inside the system because system was able to
understand but after you know ES5 ES5 okay when ES5 was introduced like this is the code that we
but after you know ES5 ES5 okay when ES5 was introduced like ECMA version 5 ES5 when I say that
they introduce something keyword called as you sticked so what they say is that when you use
this on the top of the page okay top of the JS page
JS file let me write this one so if there are any issues it throws us errors with the right messaging
or I can say better messaging so what happened is they have handled exceptional handling they
have done better in ES5 version and when you use use stick method and they gave it so now that
same use stick method is also used for react also they have launched in react 17 so 16 I guess so
we'll be exploring that in terms of firstly you will see like what one of the example I'll show
what happens with use stick non-stick but in general what have what happened is when you use
this you are supposed to write a better JS code okay let's see one of the example how that is
this affects moving back to code guys I'll start class number 21 let's say class
81 once I have this I close this one
let's say I write
okay now let's say I write down name equal to my name and I write down console.log
okay and I print name what is expected to happen this year what is expected to happen
should it be throwing error or should it be shouldn't be throwing it
okay
did I declare a variable what is the syntax of declaring a variable guys
how variables are declared firstly let's see first let's see what happens okay I'll open
integrated terminal I'll use a node strict.js
okay I'm able to print out them so is anyone amazed like how this is working firstly without
using any let const var or anything you didn't declare any variable but still it is executing
do you see this this should be a flagged write error
if it can work without using any let var const why we need to introduce that thing first place
isn't it
guys are you able to follow up so now let me show you one thing like what happens if I
use use strict here okay once I use strict and again I rerun that same file now do you see this
what use strict says that hey reference error name is not defined you didn't define the name
variable and you're trying to directly assign a value to it
are you able to see what that use strict does use strict try to follow the right side of guidelines
and rules and gives you the right sort of errors that you need in real time so this was introduced
in ECMAS 5 this was one of the examples that I wanted to show where you declare a variable
without any var let const but it gives you the right amount of error codes okay and it also
explains you properly okay so I hope you got the gist of what top level use strict and non-strict
mode is by default every js file is non-strict mode if you see whatever we were writing it down
at here everything was a non-strict now but when you use this keyword use strict you're supposed
to follow the guidelines that we have learned till now where if you don't follow it you will
be flagged that error and you can fix that one I hope this point is clear guys
guys is this point here with use strict and non-strict mode what are those things
I see three thumbs up good now so now let's say I have one question to you where
js can be compiled or passed
where js can be compiled or passed where all js can be compiled or passed
I ain't passed sorry compiled and passed where all
browser is there anything else guys browser
node yeah node js right right okay then Abhishek says the use strict will be slower than non-strict
it shouldn't be abhishek like what if like imagine you are not declaring a variable and
just trying to execute in strict non-strict mode by default behind the same system is actually
applying a variable right so they are doing the two works instead it will throw an error to us
so it's better if you go for any production-based apps you will always see a use strict flag will
be used okay any js file you go for production-based code you will see that use strict is used
it doesn't affect that performance okay now so as we know that we have the two environments
browser and node js so we'll understand this keyword with respect to all of them
but let's understand what this is talking about you know this is a keyword which usually
points to an object let me write those sentence
this keyword
always refer to an object
refer to an object and the value
of this keyword
will depend on
on how it was called
okay so basically whenever we say that let's say this dot something
this dot something you might have seen there's some many syntaxes this dot name or
trying to console log or assigning a value to it right you are using always so we are talking
about what this is standing for we all we almost we always know that this operator dot operator is
always used on objects mostly in js so we are still saying that the same thing that this is
always referring to the object and value of this particular which object we are pointing will depend
on from where it is being called okay this is a top level definition guys we'll come back to this
one we'll understand multiple times okay so that we'll get a complete just of it and we will be
exploring this in in both the browser environment and node js environment whereas both in strict
and non-strict mode okay let's start with one by one we'll pick it up one environment and we'll
see what all behaviors are there then we'll go to the next environment okay let me go back
to the code base let's let's understand this keyword in depth now okay let me build a folder
called node js so firstly we'll understand in terms of node js and i'll create a new file called non-strict
js now let's understand in terms of non-strict firstly okay i'll write down comments also so
that you can refer this whenever you feel confused let's say if i say that simple console log
what if i do console dot log this keyword in non-strict mode we say that this will always
point to an object now what can be the object initially where it can point out any ideas guys
anything that you remember window says diraj i'm in non-strict mode in terms of node js
anyone else any ideas guys
okay let's let's explore this no this this is always will point to
some of the object here okay some says empty okay let's explore this what happens okay
let's say node cd node js no non-strict dot js
okay now one of the common problem with node js is whenever you are using this contest simply
right you may not be able to you know access the object that you need it and this
generally should be pointing to a global object so here in node js environment window object is
similar to global object here they call it as a global object okay remember that thing here
but when you do simple a simple console log this this is referring to an empty object which doesn't
have any values okay there's no proper explanation to this why this behavior comes out but in node
js whenever you are trying to do console log without any context here there is no context
for this one so this is actually acting as an empty object okay now let's see what happens if i
put this put let's say this inside a function okay when i do inside a function let's say i
have a function called test and i try to do console log of this same thing
and what i'll be doing is i'll be executing this just now what could be our expectations guys
so empty empty again okay now so if you go and write down the execution process for this one
what could the execution process for this one like if you go create a memory phase and
execution phase like our code execution phase separate execution context will be created for
each function right
okay so many says it should be empty or an error but let's see what happens then if you see
here whenever we are doing inside the function now inside the function you are expected to write
this functions right set interval set timeout clear timeout all these functions you would be
writing it generally set immediate micro task you accessing global object now these all methods
these all methods are referring to a global object now inside a function will this particular this
keyword refers to an window object or a global object okay this thing you know i'll help you
to understand step by step how this works but let's explore examples more and then we'll come
back to this one so even if i show you why this happens okay if i put a debugger here let's say
if we do this
let's say i move to okay i'm here let me say i'll open here
so
okay
second guys just i'm going inside that path folder so to execute you know in terms of
testing i'm debugging more non-strict dot js
and if you see here firstly we are getting of calling a functional call if you see in the call
stack we are you know having an ominous step at line number 10 once i call this a separate
execution context is created pushed onto it where test is executed now if you see here always
it will be having an access to global object as i told you in terms of node just window object
is equaled into global object only the use case where it fails is like it will refer to an empty
object only when you are using simple console log dot but always in other cases it tries to refer
to this this refers to some object and this this object here it is trying to refer to a global object
it checks in the local scope it finds that this is pointing to global object i hope this point
is clear we'll go ahead with the next example one more thing is that let's say what happens if this
keyword is inside an object itself
okay let's see this example guys i'm trying to use as many examples as possible uh we'll try to
give you just stuff it with all different environments to understand this one okay
let's have adam uh and let's say age is of adam is something 32 and let's say we are seeing that get
it print info a function uh let's say i call an anonymous function where i try to return
or let's say we try to console dot lock here this start name
and this start h okay we did this then what if i call let's say object dot get print info if i
execute this thing what should be my output here any ideas guys what should be my output
always remember that this points to an object and where it is being called now if you see
the context here whenever i'm getting inside this it will check whether this is pointing to any object
now if you see this function context is always being changed because you are having this object
here referred and whenever in in any when if you're trying to create any key variable keep
any key value pairs and if it's a part of object it always refers to its current object okay
now let's see if this is working fine clear it if you see here i'm getting adam and 32 as printed
because here this object is referring to the current object where it is being called from so
you are using this object itself the current object dot great in print info is this clear guys
how i adam and 32 is coming are you able to follow guys
so i've shown you three of the examples where one of the thing is by default any function right if
you write a console log of this and it is outside any context and it is it is always referred to the
global execution context okay and simple this is always pointing to an empty object if this always
it will point to some object but it is either pointing to empty global or the object where it
is being called from okay now let's see another example if i write down this way let's say this
keyword from a function
that is inside a
function
inside an object now i return one j bridge line guys let's understand this one firstly okay
okay so what it says is that let's say i have an object to
you know from here again i'll use same thing name would be now instead of adam let's say we have
steve and let's say also age is something around 26 and let's say i again have the
let's say i define as a test function inside the test function i have a function
okay this this function will again have a function inside it
okay that'll revise anyways okay so now inside this function i'm trying to console dot log of this
this dot name and this dot age and also i'll try to console log of this here
so guys can you expect here what will be happening let's i'm executing g also here
and i try to call object to dot test function
so firstly let's understand this line whether this keyword from a function okay this keyword
from a function that is inside a function
inside an object so this is what it is actually meaning that particular sentence now let's
expect like what do you expect an output here can anyone think can anyone think it like what
can anyone think it like what could be the output we have seen three use cases
steve and 26 is from earth anyone else steve 26 how many of you believe that output should
be steve 26 this will point an object and steve and 26 okay great so i see one thumbs up
is anyone is all able to follow up guys i see i don't see all people reacting it if you don't
understand it at any point of time do let me know we'll try to spend time on that understanding it
okay now let me show you one thing you will be astonished to see this one the output of this
one let's say i try to comment above console locks i'll stop this execution i'll stop this
execution okay i'll stop this execution okay let's say i try to print this one now
if do you see this here what what just happened now this is pointing to
a global object and
this particular this dot name this dot is caught undefined undefined now
i've shown you output i've shown you this thing can anyone think of what could have just happened
here just see this code guys i believe you should be able to understand try to draw an
execution context for this one how it would execute it you'll be able to think what will be
able to think what will be the output for this one
okay meanwhile what i'll do is start so you are thinking it that's fine also i'll try to replicate
this in the ipad i'll show you what is exactly actually happening let's say i have that same
object const object to where i have name called steve
and age as 26 and then we have something like text function inside that we had another function
an ominous function inside that let's say i have function
g i try to console log
of this
i console log of
the start name
the start age
h i'm executing g here then i'm closing this function closing this object and i'm calling
object to dot test function this is what we are doing it right
now let's see what just actually happened
okay this is what we have just written now firstly this whenever i create an execution
context right whenever i create an execution context let's say this is an execution context
one now whenever i try down here we have two faces right
memory creation code execution now first step whenever i do it memory execution you know that
object 2 will be stored here and on a heap you will be having all the content right
and that will be referring here and then we have we say that from this object can you execute
test function now in the code execution i go and try to say that test function i execute it
right once i do this no once i do this i go here i see that in this execution context when this
test function execution context okay test function execution context when this is created
it has two things again memory creation code execution here if you see in this you have
function g which will be initialized and left and on this this is always pointing to
this particular execution context which is object 2 till here as we have this object
but now when you have g and you are trying to execute g here and it will create another
execution context of function g and here this won't be pointing to through the chain it won't
be going from here to here but it will be for this it's a separate execution context is created
so this will be pointing to global object okay and when you try to console log this you will
be see you will be seeing this one here and whereas if you try to see name and age in this
global object we don't have name and age so both will be undefined
do you guys understand this one what just happened like i just try to show you in terms of
yeah right cover okay i see one thumbs down guys can you give me further
thumbs down if you don't understand it
no okay cool i see many people who don't didn't understand it now i'll show you once
with actually you know debugging it so that again we'll come back to this one
now let's say i put a debugger here also here here okay i go back and try to execute the same file
now you guys just check it on this okay firstly when i'm when i'm executing it
in the local context or if you go for global context okay firstly it checks in local context
whether there is something like this is if there is an object or memory is loaded
okay guys i hope this you are able to see this one right this is visible enough or you are not
able to look at it okay cool now this is a call stack now at call stack we are at the line number
37 if you see 3776 it's it shows it highlights that one and here in the memory you have object
two and object one now let's see what happens when you go inside this function whenever you
are trying to execute the test function okay now i click the play button now if you see whenever
i'm going to the new function test function there's a new thing that i got added into
call stack now when you whenever you see this one right so i've told you that initially when
memory loads this is the step one that is happening then you have the execution context two
which is for test function okay which is pushed onto the call stack here when i go inside this
if you see when i go inside this test function still this object is referring to the globe or
this object too because that is calling this function that is calling this function and it
is wrapped with these names okay so if you expand this one if you see age and name and age will be
available here is this point clear till now how the test function is able to access this name and
age because that is that is itself calling right so as i told you here this will be always pointing
to the object to itself because it is acting as a wrapper yes i see only one thumbs up can you give
me thumbs up if you are able to understand this how we are able to access age and name inside the
test function uh i don't see any reactions
okay cool now what happens let's see what happens let's see here if i go and create call the function
g now a new execution context will be created altogether if you see a new execution context
created for this it is this is pointing to global it doesn't have any context related to
previous functions previous object it doesn't remember this thing it doesn't remember because
this is completely getting executed in altogether different context it doesn't have any understanding
of what is happening in the previous so this thing you will be able to refer better when you
think in terms of this way okay this is a step one this is the step two then you will see that
g function is a step three okay this is one where you have an object you loaded memory you are
calling test function then you execute text function where you have access to this keyword
because the object to dot test function something we are calling an object to data will be there
once test function execution starts we say that we need to execute g function once we go for g
for every function we know that the separate execution context is created and once it starts
it it always points to as we know and this this is behaving same way as this one isn't it
if you see here also we wrote a simple function always execute uh points to global object
isn't it
guys is this clear like how this thing is this thing is working so how many of you uh are able
to relate with execution context process like did anyone practice it once we learned in hoisting
concept uh because there we practiced it i've drawn execution context diagram so hopefully
you are able to relate with this one okay now so let's let me revise again guys for you all
so if you see it here i've took four examples first example was simple when i tried to console
lock this in non-strict mode it always point to an empty object okay let me write here empty object
okay this is one of the edge case where you will be seeing a different output
but when it comes to function dot test it will this will point to the global object which
it refers to in new execution context that we we just seen this okay and when it comes to object
when you're trying to access this i mean inside the object it will always refers to its same object
where it is calling from okay then you have a i mean a function inside a function which is
inside an object then this will be executing in a separate execution context so this will
behave as a simple function and the simple function we know that it always points to a global object
okay is this clear guys i hope i revised it again you are able to get through it so one thing we'll
do is that one thing we'll do whenever we are going through these four examples we'll try to
make a notes of this one here so that you can come back and see remember these examples let's say
i write down for the
nojs and this is non-stick mode
okay here let's say first example was simple we know that console log this
object what this points to guys
this always points to some object but which object would be pointing it in simple the console of
this context empty right let me write down this one in second example we had this inside a function
and wherever it's inside a function what it points to
is a global object right and then we have another example this is inside an object
okay let me write down this way
this is inside a function and that function is inside an object and i'm calling object dot
function and what will be the output for this one
think of this one this is the same example i'm calling object dot function
if you see this i'm calling here object dot function so i was able to get the object itself
right now here can i say that here it will be our object itself
as output
guys are you able to follow up
okay great now then there was something that we tried experimenting on this inside and function
and which is again inside and function and which is part of object now here
we are again calling object dot funk when we are doing this we got global object
right i hope this differences are clear these four examples
so usually this keyword confuses you so i'm trying to you know note down all the possible
use cases which will give you a gist of it completely when we complete for the all the
modes okay let's go and explore the same use cases same examples in the strict mode how this thing
how this thing behaves okay
now we'll go to something called a strict mode let's say i go to a strict mode and i remove this
one and let's say i try to control dot log of this now what could be the expectation in the strict
mode because strict mode was acting as an enhancement and by default do you think there
should uh without any context this should be pointing to something
all right we think that it should be creating an error but there is a one of the edge case guys
one of the you know default exception case you can say for this one simple console log
but because if you see the output
it still points to an empty object this is without meaning in non-strict mode or strict mode it is
always pointed to an empty object is this clear like always uh this one simple console log this
will point to empty object whether it is strict or non-strict when it comes to node.js environment
okay now let's say that i go and try to replicate this function okay let's say this thing i copy
and i paste it here now think of it what it should be pointing to
uh let me remove this
in the strict mode uh do they have any object available here
global function right let's explore this okay do you see this it is printing undefined
in the strict mode there is nothing as such that you will be able to access uh in simple function
like you won't be having any global function by default attached to it
you have to define a context for that if there is only context for that
only then you will be able to access that global function global object uh to say
is this clear guys how the strict mode is saving for saving us like trying to protect from
all the sites the all the errors that we see that you know all the use cases that creates
this confusion when you use a strict mode it simplifies our pain point okay now let's
see uh with the third example if i pick it up this example
let's say comment let's say i have here i'll say this points to
undefined okay now what would be the output for this one guys uh object where we are trying to
print get print info are we binding this operator with this object so i done 32 says the edge how
many of you agree with the edge point of view
how many of you agree with the edge point of view
i see two people so i hope you understand the reason behind why you are agreeing because
we say that him using this object itself we are calling this function and this will always have
an access to this one in its context in its local context itself uh and this will be always printing
the right thing so there is no magic if you see adam 32 sprinting here okay so it is working
in a right format now if i pick it up fourth one this example if i pick it up fourth example
what should be the output
now this is calling from object inside an object
earlier it was pointing to a global object but what this will point to
to undefined how many of you agree with or disagree with guys pradeep and diraj
here agree right great let's see if this is giving me undefined okay now it gives me undefined it
also throws me an error that you cannot read the property name and age if you see earlier uh if you
see earlier in non-stick mode we didn't get this error isn't it we got undefined simply undefined
isn't it for name and age also but here in the strict mode as i told you earlier that when you
use use strict flag it gives us the right understanding of errors it gives throws us
errors that we need to see it says that type error cannot read properties earlier if i still
execute this point right if i still go and execute this file non-stick mode i'll show you the
difference what happens
you see i'm getting undefined undefined pointing to window object you see this there's a difference
here it is returning as undefined but whereas in strict mode it throws us error so this was
an implementation that uh you stick flags giving us i hope you understand this
okay guys are you following up great now let's let's fill in this blanks that we were preparing
notes for now in the strict mode what this console log adopt this prints
what does it prints for the first one console empty right still and second one when we are
inside the function the stick mode undefined
and in the third one still do we print object
data right object itself in the fourth one
error and undefined both things right so i'll write here undefined because i'm i haven't written
logic just i'm trying to say that what how the context switching is happening so i hope everyone
is but having a clarity here like how things are differing in terms of strict and non-stick mode
with respect to node chase environment and with these examples is anyone having any challenge
understanding this one do let me know guys if you want me to repeat it give me thumbs up if you
want me to repeat it again completely or else if you want me to go ahead give me thumbs down
okay i see people are asking me to repeat it once i see three four okay great okay let's say uh i'll
repeat it once uh so what i was saying is that you know always this operator uh refers to some
object now that object we have to figure it out whether it's an empty object or the object is
doesn't exist or whether it's a global object or window object or the object itself that we are
calling on now that which type of object that uh this is pointing to depends upon how it is being
called so the basic definition is always this points to an object but we need to know how
how this is changing because this changes depends on how it is being called okay
now we have seen in the strict a non-strict environment that whenever we are trying to do
a simple console log this is an uh you know exception case uh you do it in strict and
non-strict mode it always points to an empty object okay it doesn't mean anything but when
it comes inside a function uh if you go for non-strict mode it always refers to a global
object where you can access all the set timers set time or functions you know uh set interval
all those functions inside the non-strict mode okay and when it comes to a simple object here
if you see the way we are calling this function get print info function we are calling this function
using the object itself so the context of this changes to this object this is always pointing
to this object itself okay and inside that object memory we have add a name and h so we are able to
print name and h here okay so if we go for the next example if you see it here till if you say
object to dot test function wherever we are calling this function of this test function
we always have the this operator append pointing to this object to this test function will have an
access to name and age but when this g function is getting executed it executes an altogether
separate execution context where there is no object that is particularly calling this function
so whenever it is getting created as an empty use case it behaves in a same way as a simple function
and when this happens it always this refers to a global object and this dot name and age are
set to undefined because global object doesn't have name and age whereas if you go for strict mode
still see this is an edge case so it still points to an empty object generally in the strict mode
it behaves as we look at it now when we say that we are trying to print something this operate
directly inside a function there is nothing like we're defining an object here so it always point
to undefined whereas for this example we are strictly straightforwardly defining that hey
object to dot great print info and we are doing this this particular object already have this name
and it so it is giving us that output and when coming to this one again this function is acting
as a simple function and there is no this keyword pointing to anything there's no context for this
one so it gives us undefined and for this one we it throws an error type error i hope the
guys i hope you are able to follow up and things are clear now how this works in strict and
non-strict mode which comes with respect to node.js environment now let's explore
how this thing changes with with respect to browser because we know that you know js works
in both the environments now we have explored one part of it now let's explore this in the
second part of it okay going to browser and again non-strict.js let's say i try to copy this code
whatever code i have let's say i comment or else let's say we type it down one by one
let's pick one by one okay and if we want to if we want to execute a file in the browser we have
to have a one html file okay let's say i'll remove this one let's say i have an index html file
and this index html let's say i have this and we
define script we have source tag
non-strict.js let's say i say strict versus non-strict
okay let me refine this other day i'll copy this
context of this key let's say we write this thing and i launch this html
so i haven't done anything great guys so just a thing that i created an html connected with this
non-strict file and i try to console lock this simple thing now what do you think in terms of
browser this points to when i do the console log of this one any guesses you might have played
around with a browser many times till now you might not have used node.js environment as as much as
environment as as much as we have used document or window says zrash okay let's see this case
no one thing i want to know why do you think document zrash just want to understand your
point of view document is a dom api right and that is not an object which is having all the
functions that we need it will always point to a window object okay which have all the browsers
functions available in it submit as in terms of node.js as we had edge case in strict and
non-strict it was pointing to an empty in terms of browser it will always point to window okay
this is also another edge case okay so here guys if you see if i try to write down simple this here
what do you see see this window is building out if i say this dot document
so document is a part of window object itself zrash this dom is a part of whole object that's
a whole object which is having everything okay document will be there but it's a part of window
itself you will see when i open the window right in the browser you will have too many things
too many methods available if you go and try to use navigation right a location based too many
events too many things that you will be able to see what all things that you can see on the browser
that all things will be available here you'll be able to see performance and you know
be able to see in the window object so simply in non-strict mode when it comes to browser simple
console of this points to the window now let's say in function okay let's say yeah that's that's
depending on how you know the js is executed i don't because now if a browser is built by
different teams node js is built by one of the different open source organization
they called it that way particularly that's how you write you've been writing the code legacy code
indirectly in browser you can access like the timer functions and everything okay that's how
the wrapper has been built whereas in node js it behaves differently okay
so let's say console lock this and let's say if i execute test now
what do you guys think what was the answer for this one in the node js environment
anyone remember it in the non-strict mode
global right here as i told you in node js if it is a global is equal to window object let's see
if this is working fine okay i go back here i try to console log if you see still we are able to see
window object coming from the line number five okay this line number five is this one itself
okay i hope this is clear now this global and window object name is convention is also changed
by the respective teams who build this node js framework and you know browser okay now let's
see the third example which is this one and i hope this is a straightforward example one final check
uh one final check guys would be the output still same for this one
would you see the adam in 32 still getting printed for this use case let's see let's see this
okay do you see that adam in 32 is printing so when it comes to this use case it's a straightforward
right object is calling and this will always point to the object so in those use cases it's
straightforward and simple now let's go and try to execute this use case
no
do you think still it should point to global object in a separate execution context
for this one
someone says no
okay okay still if you see as i told you earlier this will work like a
same function as this one right a simple function in a new execution content it was
pointing to window this will also be pointing to the window object okay
so
now let's see do you see it here it points to window object and it throws an undefined here
reason behind we are trying to access this one if i try to comment this one you will be able to see
only window i hope these points are clear guys like how in terms of non-strict environment
browser is behaving the only change is again this console of this this behaves by default
it provides us access to window and all the use cases you see window object getting printed or
the subject itself right let's try to fill in the notes that we are preparing for understanding
okay let's say
i write down as browser
okay and i say that non-strict mode
simple console log of this so what was this pointing to guys again
uh you'll help me out right writing this thing down so
window right inside this also window isn't it this inside the function
now the third example was this inside a function which was a part of object and we were calling
object dot function and we should be able to print object itself here this is a common across
each environment strict non-strict browser or anything now this inside a function inside a
function and that is inside an object right and this points to again window
is this clear guys like how this works in the non-strict environment
is this clear guys like how this works in the non-strict environment with respect to browser
you know i'm doing this exercise for on this particular keyword is because
people get confused so you should be able to understand how this works
if you are clear with the execution context point of view you will be always be able to figure out
other than this one of the edge case okay now let's go and see what happens in the strict mode
let me create inside a browser strict dot js and let me link
strict dot js once i link this i'll go to this file i'll try to print this one now what do you
think guys the output should be in the strict dot js in terms of browser and define let's see
this if this is working that way browser always gives you window object as i told you the edge
case for this one is that in as in strict and non-strict mode always console log okay let's
me use that that one use strict okay let me go back you see this see this i refresh it
now as i told you this is one of the edge case that happens like in simple console log this
either it is pointing to empty object or like it is pointing to window object here in both
in strict and non-strict mode this is pointing to window object okay now let's see if i write
down a function again test inside the console dot log
this and let's say i execute this here now what would you expect here again
in the strict mode what was from earlier experience what would be the output in terms of
node js strict mode
undefined isn't it there in node js let's see what happening here still do you see this undefined
that those both are aligned because there is no binding object binding is happening here there
is no context for this one this okay now let's go with the third example which we have now
this should be pretty straightforward that each time because this is one of the valid use case
it should be still printing adam32 right it's still printing adam32
now then there's one of the other last case
let's say i try to take this and print it
it now what should this point to here guys
again undefined isn't it let's see so i guys align how this is working
in the strict mode same way so which environment do you find better guys
this strict mode now let's say i write down here in the notes that first point
it's still pointing to window object this one it points to undefined
this points to object itself
this points to undefined
so which is a better environment for to use for the production spaces just let me know whether
you would use strict or non-strict which would be preferred guys from your understanding strict
right strict mode is preferred and when it goes to that's the only difference if you see the
outputs right if i zoom it out when it comes to strict or non-strict both the things this one or
this one only the this use case right first use case are behaving differently but in all other
use cases you'll be able to see that they are behaving in a same way okay so in production
basis we go with the strict mode and this is what you have to remember i've but i have given you
the context of everything which i'll be again taking a screenshot and i'll be adding that into
you know as i've added it for these two things like you have a debouncing throttling the topics
whichever you feel confusing right like the position property i'll be adding an image for
this one so that you remember it if you are not able to access this notes whatever we are preparing
i'll add this one if you need it do you want me to add it add this one there guys this differences
block okay great i'll do that i have to prepare this one i'll add this one there okay great so
are you feeling confident about like understanding this this is always again repeating the you know
definition definition of this is like this this is pointing to some object now this object can be of
how many types it can be window or global depending upon which node chase or the
like browser then you have sometimes it object itself sometimes it is undefined
now the undefined gives whenever in the considering strict mode if no context
like there is nothing like whenever you're executing you are simply calling that function
like function dot whenever you're calling this without any object context then you it will give
you undefined whenever you're calling from the object point of view it will always print object
itself and this is by window and global is like in strict mode when you will be able to access guys
only in simple console lock this other times you won't be able to access
directly the reason they have done right in strict mode you will be only able to
access the window or empty object from friend end point of view in browser is that
you always try to add this set timeout and everything right
okay so the definition is simple this is pointing to some object we should know where it is being
called from once this point is clear you will be able to figure it out
so guys do you need a break or should i go ahead i need another half an hour to complete the class
if you need a break so you can go ahead and complete the class and then you can go ahead and
i need another half an hour to complete the class if you need a break let me know
or else if you want me to continue i can continue okay you need a break how many minutes guys
so we'll use some bits application some say seven some say ten okay so
okay what i'll do is that i'll give it for seven minutes guys so i'm starting a timer
once it is clocking seven minutes so i hope some bit you will improve this application redeploy
and give it to me where i can enter the number of minutes okay i'm just waiting to clock it seven
next week surely done so i've started guys take the break and come back in seven minutes
you
uh guys i hope everyone is back can you give me one thumbs up if you are back guys
cool uh so one check can anyone check if in archive section do you see
github uh class and uh you know portfolio project class is added
i got confirmation today i've been asking for some days uh but can you check
so
is anyone confirming guys is anyone checking
so please go through those classes guys it will really help you to fill up the other content which
is not been covered so okay
great uh again uh i would again ask you like you know uh whatever classes are there please
try to go to check them once you have bandwidth uh even if you need any other content other than
this thing if we are missing any topic or anything you can uh you know mention to me in whatsapp group
or anywhere visionary or in class we'll try to cover it up we'll try to pick it up okay
but can we move it guys can we move it the next topic
great so let's say next topic is uh something called as constructor function
before going to its name or anything what it is let's let's do something let's build something okay
let's say i create a file called constructor
dot j s now let's say
let's say let's just think of this one that what if you want to build an car what all things you need
let's say you went to a tata factory uh let's say you say that
hey this is a car one uh what all properties it can have firstly
color model can i say name firstly let's say it will have some name and then color then model
and features all these are features itself upendra so company have fixed this is a tata
manufacturing date can i use another top speed keyword let's say four things okay
now let's say that uh one of the car arun suggestors is nexon let's say nexon tata nexon
now inside nexon which color you want it arun which color i pick it any color guys nexon looks
cool cool in coral do we have coral nexon available okay let's say nexon
nexon
petrol okay then you have a top speed of nexon as let's say 160 kmph
okay this is an object now if you want to create an another object
bumblebee uh okay but let's come back to this guys if you want to build how many other car
like in tata factory there are many other models also are being built right now if you want to
build another model which would be you're picking up tiago let's say you have a tiago
and let's say color of tiago is a black and let's say this is uh electrical
model
and let's say this runs on up to 160 kmph still tiago i'm not sure but it goes okay safari
this is one of my favorite model no one mentioned it yet i'm seeing comments
tiago only 80 let me give 100 at least
safari okay let's say safari is red in color it's a petrol engine heavy uh sorry diesel engine
heavy vehicle uh and it goes up to 240 kmph no yeah i was waiting for this harrier have you been
waiting for this harrier have you been in harrier guys have you experienced harrier
have you seen harrier it's it's it's literally wow for me uh it's really classical car
i really like it
i mean my neighbors have it we give it my car to him i pick it up other car
so yeah uh yes there's one more car uh kind of a hatchback can you guess it
but it's really cool car also yeah altros right let's say i pick it up altros
hey this will go up to 240
altros let's say it's blue in color
uh it's again petrol let's let's say it goes up to 160 kmph now yes uh we have uh ferrari it's not
part of tata motors so if you see here there's one thing what we are doing is that the one way
of creation object is this way right whenever object whenever see where object what we are
actually meant to say that we are trying to envision the real time entity right a real time
entity like a car it can have a number of properties yeah uh classes i don't want to
talk in terms of class some bit we didn't introduce the word class or we don't know what class is
but let's just talk in terms of objects functional objects or javascript objects that we discussed
but are you able to relate like if i give any real time entity or real world entity you will
be able to create objects this way like defining a space square i mean curly braces and defining
its properties and functions in it right you will be able to relate with any any real world entity
like take it a house take it a building take it apartment or anything you will be able to
relate it right anything you will be able to build it this way yeah providing reality to idea
because this is where objects helps you to connect with you real time things like you can
build even if you want to build a macbook or windows you can keep on defining properties
functions everything so you'll be able to do that so now but do you see here some use cases
like if i want to build n number of cars let's say if i want to build i feel i build five cars
i have defined five objects specifically to it okay like car 1 car 2 car 3 car 4 car 5 each time
i'm trying to type a car name model top speed right so i'm trying to duplicate i'm duplicating
the code here do you see this this is a duplication code duplication happening
so imagine now even what if i want altros of red in color i don't have a way if i want to create
altros of red in color i have to create another object of altros red what if i need altros blue
of desert i have to create another object so if i'm trying to build that way there's a lot of
you know the code gets lengthy and you know way of defining the objects is really it looks not
that you know good to eyes right whenever you see that code so in order to fix these issues there
is a one of the other way how you can define this object creation one of the way you can create
object is this way in js the other way is something called as constructor function
but do you know what constructor is called in any language whenever you say that whenever you
hear this word constructor what do you exactly understand by this keyword
what do you understand by this keyword call constructor
any idea what do you understand by this keyword call constructor
in any language go to java python c++ anything that you bring there is a this keyword is common
across each and every language but i just want to understand what do you exactly understand by this
keyword call constructor anyone
called every time an object is created somebody says and any other definitions guys do you
remember any other definitions
okay
is anyone trying out anyone from java backgrounds that's one of the basic color definition
any object-oriented programming so there were many people
who were working around with java object-oriented programming
so just want to know what do you understand a function to create or initiate object okay
okay it's like creating ones initializing constructor using multiple to create object
okay great now one of the you know clarity that i want to give it to all you is that
you know constructor is used to initialize object variables
in order to create object
you use new keyword generally new keyword is something which is creating memory
right which is creating an empty memory for you where in constructor you pass on the values which
initializes the variables right whatever you define it in a class like i don't want to say that but
if you want to relate it that way so do you agree with this definition
okay guys whoever commented in the chat do you agree with this definition
now and i just want to know in the class how many of you are able to understand this thing
firstly i hope there are many people who don't understand these two sentences even
okay great now i hope everyone is able to relate it but now let's see how do you do it in javascript
if you want to create these objects like you want to reduce the amount of this code duplicacy and
how would you do it so one of the thumb rule for creating a you know constructor function is
whichever function you are creating if you are trying to make it as a runner as a constructor
function you have to define that function starting with a capital letter let's say
i say it as data cars do you see i have mentioned capital t there okay this is first thing now
inside this data car it will receive a list of variables now let's say you have this name color
model and top speed okay these are the variables that you have now in order to create these
variables what i'll do it here is something i'll just show you guys you have to tell me
whether this will work or not
the start model
equal to model the start top speed equal to top speed
okay just let me know whether this will work or not
okay now what i did it here is start now let's say if i if i create a new memory how can i call
this function if i want to create an object anytime let's say i am creating a const altros
if i'm trying to create an altros here let's say i will say that hey can you give me a new car
and uh let's say tata car inside that i'll give all the information i need
i'll say that this is in altros
and let's say i'll give the customization let's say blue i'll say model is electric
and i'll say top speed is 180 kmph
okay now the let's let's see if this i'm able to execute as expected uh what i'll do is i'll try
to console log this object okay then i'll try to explain what's happening behind the scenes
first let me see if this is working fine
constructor dot js
if you see it here i'm printing something called a star tata car with this all things now but what
is exactly happening here let's understand what happens when i call this function
uh when i call this function let's say new dot tata car what do you think this will be initialized
what do you think this will be initialized with
can i say step one
would be whenever you are creating an object whenever you are trying to initialize using a
new tata car whenever you say this this first thing initializes a new empty object here
i mean this is pointed to an empty object because you created a whole whole together new object
is this clear guys step one what is happening whenever you use new keyword you are generally
creating a whole together new object which this is pointing to this empty object once this is done
then wherever you have this variables right wherever you have this variables this start
name model it takes those all those variables whatever defined in the function it takes those
variables let's say it takes this like this start name is always pointing to undefined
like then the start model values will be undefined okay the start color undefined the start color
undefined so this is how this will be working in second step like all the way
initial first is empty object then this object then at step three all these values will be
filled with actual data now this object whatever object you have it with this will point this will
change to such a way that this will point to an object which will have name auditors
then you'll have color let's say blue then you'll have model as electric
then you'll have top speed as some random value
so are you able to relate to this case how actually object is being created using constructor function
okay even this doesn't work this way it takes like a model it initializes all values with the
undefined like same like a memory execution execution phase all the variables first initialize
with undefined okay this is what happening in the second step then third step it is this is
what it is building it now if i want to rebuild all of these models right it's really simple
right one of the simple use cases would be for me to it's like replicate this one let's say i want
to create a safari i'll go and say that get me the new car i'd say safari color would be red
uh color would be red model would be petrol
uh top speed will be let's say 240 kmph right so i hope you are able to
connect with this case how concept of functions are used how can you optimize the code the way
you write right i can end up this in five lines of code like if i can create a number of objects
that we want so hope you are able to know understand the new way of creating an object
uh like if you have a really reusable object let's say each and every object will be having
a same sort of fields like say they will be having the same sort of fields then we will be using this
one right like we can write a constructor function and we can reuse it this is the one of the core
concepts of javascript now i hope you got to know now two ways of creating objects in js
one is simple using curly braces then you will have constructor function so why we when we need
to go to constructor function the only in the use case where you have the where you have to create
a multiple objects with similar variables or even that's the same definition right when you
want to go for a class whenever you have multiple objects are of same type or with changing the
types of variables but i'll come back to the class in the next class i hope this point is
clear guys anyone having any doubts why constructor function and how constructor function works
okay can you please scroll to the first method uh step what if you miss a variable in the
uh new constructor okay what if we missed it let's say i try to build it up that way like color
uh let me miss this okay let's say i have i don't have this color okay let's say
let's say i have i don't have this color okay let's say i've gave only three values now
okay uh let's say i try to print safari
here if you see it here what happened whenever you miss some variable here
so it or the last variable will be assigned undefined
like it the petrol was assigned earlier so that's how it works as per index
as per index other than that thing like it's not as per index but if you see i'm picking name then
i'm applying yeah like you can say the the exact way that how it is defined in the parameters the
same way you have to pass the arguments the function okay
so great guys guys any anything else any doubts if you don't have any doubts uh so uh today's
classes that's that much itself because i don't want to confuse you introducing new things like
classes as of now but this is what today we are talking about like what this is talking about
this context of this in no like understanding strict and non-strict environments and both
like how this works in both browser and node.js then understanding a constructor function
up to an extent then we'll come back with the new topics again right samvith yeah we have
ended the content that we have to discuss for today
so if there are no doubts can i start doubt session and we can go ahead
great guys so let's say i start the doubt session
okay so i've started out session guys but uh what i'll we'll be doing it right uh something
i just want to talk about it once i introduce classes
yeah uh we started early quite early today right uh doubt session but uh next in next class we
actually will start with actual object-oriented programming that you reflex with which is esx
syntaxes esx concepts where you see classes and classical inheritance and then we'll try to see
how they have built it actually what is the behind the scenes you know how they were able to build
this class samvith was waiting for ankit's reactions things so guys uh so i i knew that
i was able i'll be closing up early today that's the reason why i asked people who were facing
challenge i'll be discussing with them so guys uh earlier uh whoever gave me thumbs down right
who were not able to follow up with the class or the content uh let's have the conversation
uh just you know raise your hand so that i'll unmute you we can have discussed broadly we'll
understand your points i'll try to add my uh you know my vision or my way of understanding
how can you do it better
uh good night guys if uh if there are no doubts feel free to drop uh we'll connect back on the
thursday uh okay kiran's has shared me uh you know kanban board get kiran let me share it to everyone
okay uh i'll come to come to you for a second so this is built by kiran kudos to kiran for building
it uh putting all the efforts so one suggestion i can give you is that you know the font size are
really small if you can improve a bit big uh would be really cool this one this are all to do okay
this one this are all to do okay maybe a little bit bigger okay uh no screen size
okay i see search filter going at below so i just want to see uh
uh yeah i it's looking a bit different on my system i agree so there might be few things
breaking uh yeah uh we have to address that issues we have to address that issues like how why it is
breaking let's say if i give you some pointers uh let's say i zoom it out
hey it was working fine
now if you see uh at 100 zoom uh the search is going inside it but when i'm opening debugger
i'm able to see that one now if you see how this is working this been added or dealt with
with
or the search container css position relative uh position relative to which one is this this
container with this container if you do seven rem uh when i
when i when i do this right when i play around with this my screen sizes and width it will be
breaking this one search container what if i remove this
i remove this by default uh
let's say we have a wrapper around here i say display as a flex
and flex direction as a column
let's say as of now um i'm just editing i'm trying to figure it out okay when i put this
column reverse uh it still goes inside because this toolbox container is defined in terms of
height of 15 percent 15 percent of width let's say you give some
let's say 25 pixels uh 250 pixel which is too huge 100 pixels try to use relative unit so that
it would be good kiren right in terms of uh use relative units you'll be able to figure it out
use rems okay now if you see uh once i fix that 15 pixel one even if i go and try to use your
properties like if i use this now let's say i go and remove this display flexion direction
this works fine i have to only address this issue i guess this whatever height you are using 15vh
that's the thing which was creating an issue okay uh and another uh keep check this font sizes uh
use relative units as per screen width it will change it okay uh keep it default
using rem units so that will work fine uh trying to create ticket uh this looks cool
let's say i again use task one uh and i click pink so i have a really yeah the highlighter is
you can add a much more box shadow because box shadow is of same color and the background is
same color right so that the click feel the click feel is not that up to an extent maybe
ticket this feedback as a positive way okay hope you are not feeling offended okay
because we all are learning right now once i click so how do this ticket get created
what key i should use here what you have decided shift or enter or how does it work
because i'm trying shift and enter it's not working
okay option alt key okay great so i have alt uh now let's say i create another task task hyphen
two i have green in color i click alt and then i inspect it i go to application
and storage uh let's say okay uh one thing do you see ticket content i have task hyphen one
slash n now if i go and edit it i don't have that slash n which is like entered into the next line
check this this bug can exist in all the apps like created across okay this slash n because
i clicked enter and then pressed alt like alt yeah trim would work trim would work
okay check check on that kiran okay if that works now i'll update it as zero one and again i click
alt uh i lock this button so it got updated as expected let's say if i update color it is
expected working as expected to be review cool in progress cool to do nothing double click
uh how do i get all okay all all is the button you have given all okay will that matter
uh it is a usual string right let's say if i create uh what what will happen let's say i create
another task file i'll show it here uh let's say i say task hyphen three and i'll keep on
entering it since it's a text area i've came to last time i click uh pink as a default color
i come back here i click alt now if you see what happens do you see here the text content what if
you are sending this data to api you will be having slash and slash and slash n so this will
matter when you're actually sending it to server so trimming it is a better option
you get that okay great so yeah it is great kiran like only one css fix that i see uh which is
respect to height of ph and other things are looking cool only font sizes and good one so
if i filter it out let's say task okay uh do you see this
okay uh it's case sensitive isn't it kiran's case sensitive so one suggestion again here
uh try to use uh like uh not make in sensitive uh let's say case insensitive we should make this
one maybe use lower two lower case or two upper case anything works okay uh anything that you
are trying to check like uh the check condition uh let's say if you uh there are too many console
locks also try to remove this console locks from the application uh things are getting printed so
one of the way that i was talking about is let's say this is a task uh you will always have a two
local uppers case i don't think two local two upper case okay and so you can always triple check
with task to upper case you have to do use uh for both the conditions something that you are getting
it from uh local storage and the value which is area okay you will be able to get this way
and you'll be able to filter it and return or based on the filter
got this hidden uh this point okay yeah uh and the other one is like if i enable delete uh
let's say i hey this is cool samit you got a new point to implement our c on this one
so if i hover over it again kiren there's a one suggestion what do i do it if i hover over it
do i get a different feel no like i'm able to delete this one what if this bulges up again
again like i'm just adding my idea uh like uh whenever i'm hovering over it the cursor should
change to pointer first then only you will be able to know that you are going to delete this
pattern this particular card uh particular task so at least cursor make a change of cursor
whenever on hover the cursor will change to pointer
uh
yeah uh no no no worries no worries uh no worries uh i all like i understand it right
yeah can we make it a burst uh you can actually you can make changes uh but uh i would say even
if you did it in hurry right uh you you really got some great changes you can keep on like
you know improving it yeah uh yeah you you you can do that right you can do it you can keep on
implementing i have so that's where our ideas come right uh as a front-end developers if you
see the same application functionalities are same the app that i built was different the sam with
version was different your version was different uh those two functionalities are same so uh kudos
to your efforts guys so try to think like how can improve uh because it will help you to improve
your uh ui ux skills more and css skills more i would say like yeah because those
devs are still going to exist uh the functionality is still going to exist the same way it's just
that you are playing around with the css and some of some of your ux ideas okay so try to improve
uh like i mean i won't say that improve maybe whatever idea clicks inside your mind try to
implement that because i i feel if you are able to come for this the only deployment took two
hours truth and i get that uh okay uh even if null check is also not needed uh one thing i suggested
you know optional chaining also you can take it up get an optional chaining i suggested in the chat
uh that will also work uh yeah null check uh all optional chaining if you add it here optional
chaining now this will also work because it checks now if object is empty it won't go for for each
okay optional chaining i have already taught you know uh let's say uh
let's say this is uh let me go to some random file
let's say i say this is an index dot js okay let's say this was an array right empty array
so on this forage was breaking so let's say array dot forage uh whatever element i have i'm trying
to print it
right this is what we were doing it now now if i try to go and execute this file let's say
i'm supposed to get an undefined error you know or else let's say uh earlier we were actually
you know since this is an array this will still work let's say a node index dot js it will still
work it won't output anything but earlier on the step two we were getting values from
you know local storage or else it is setting as undefined now if i do this you see i get forage
as a property of undefined now whenever i want to handle this issue one of the check is i can do
null check or any undefined check or else i can add this condition when i add this if you see i
still don't get any error because this checks uh whether if there are only values only then
it will execute it okay so this is an optional changing if find it checks like if array is not
empty go for the next method if array is like that sort of things like okay i hope you got this uh
try to use this use case like if you don't want to use that null check
no null check works null checks works by default but i'm saying that better way of writing is like
this optional changing
so uh i had to stringify store it in local yeah yeah string because local storage stores only
strings you have to convert json's into strings and only then you can store it you have to parse
it you have to parse back whenever you are using it that happens with even api api sometimes
doesn't send you json you have to parse it uh then you have to use it so you should know that
those those are like uh yeah okay no no worries no worries uh going back to the people who wanted
to discuss here uh ankit how you doing i just want to know how are you going well is your
preparation yeah thank you kiran thank you for putting effort so you are getting to learn and
apply those knowledge okay uh try to improve on this one uh but hey one thing guys uh since
classes are added i since you have now three apps right uh of a portfolio app or weather app uh and
this one like to do list app why don't you integrate them if someone can integrate them
okay trying to link portfolio app uh with a link
oh okay your health is not good um but let me know ankit if i can help you out by some way
uh if you want me to connect with you in any session we can maybe discuss a strategy
which can help you to you know cope up with the things uh once you are you are good now
yeah going good good now or like you still your health is affected
uh job is affecting my studies too much okay uh that thing here uh it's it's like you know tricky
thing if you
look uh okay so one of the way i consider it right one of the way i say strictly right
it's not to be said this way but i should say it like what happens in job is that uh like
uh do you follow agile process in your system
agile do you follow agile okay no yes okay so if you're following agile you always have a
story points right when you start the sprint so i always uh what i do is that
i discuss with my leads uh and think that you know if a sprint a sprint is usually at my place
is of two weeks okay in two weeks we have to estimate how much amount of work we'll do
so for us when i go for two weeks i have 10 days of working with four week uh leaves or four weekends
or four weekends right so i have 10 days so what i pick is like i pick 10 story points work
not more than that if there is something ad hoc if there is something ad hoc like let's say let's
say there is something i don't which happens usually okay if there is something i don't that
you want to do or you want to work on something what i do is that again i go to jeera board
i say that if i'm working on ad hoc story i'll add those points there hey that i work two story
points of work this one so i'll reduce two points story work i'll move it to the next sprint
because this is what you are getting paid for not more than 10 story points
if you are doing it more than that then your manager is able to leverage you better
and doing this 10 story punch should you should be able to quantify it because i'll tell you it's
not today's time even if you change your job after putting off so much of hard work uh whenever you
go to let's say you cracked amazon or fang mang or anything or a good product based mnc or any
company that you want to even if you go there you have to know like how much work you should be able
to take it how much you would be able to deliver it because when it comes to work-life balance
no company provides work-life balance it is up to you how do you choose it i've seen in paypal
or any aux that i worked in people working 16 17 hours whereas i was working only for the amount
of thing that i was paid because i was always upscaling myself focusing on things that i wanted
myself focusing on things that i wanted to learn as an engineer okay so considering these things
you should always set up you mean you should fight for yourself because end of the day when
when your appraiser hits when your appraiser hits your manager has 100 rupees in his bucket
he have to distribute between the whole team doesn't matter if you work 18 20 hours he won't
get extra like someone is working of more than nine hours of time that is working extra five six
hours he won't get extra money like 120 or 130 per year in order to distribute if he's getting
it's it's good to put in those efforts but he's not getting it so he'll be having only 100 rupees
he'll be distributing it so first thing is communication understanding how do you drive it
whether it's your business analyst who's driving the scrum or scrum master the respective product
owner or the client or your manager lead whoever is a stakeholder you have to understand how do
you build it how do you build it so that you have to manage your time otherwise you'll keep on
otherwise you'll keep on working and you won't be able to learn things other than your work
this is clear guys like there's a strategy that you have to build
uh so that okay i'll come to your use case and uh kit now because i'm not uh like because i have
been into this role right i know how things work so i was talking about that from that perspective
but from your perspective uh i would say that
it's it's it's six months hard work
somehow
how maybe while you're i agree i agree uh i agree that but but you know six months hard work from
scratch if you are able to put on effort i'll give you my time also to help you out to you know do
it but if you if you are doing it then i'll be also doing it okay if you have any challenge i'll
be also doing it but if you should be putting it from your side so that i can contribute from my
i'll be available you can ping me but it's it's that
you have to find time i cannot i even i need it i need it like i need more than 25 even sometimes
i have too much workload i'm my eyes are burning right now uh my day started morning seven i want
system for continuous okay so but there are some days you'll have tough days there are some days
you'll have good days okay but it's it's our job like we will be should be able to figure it out
how we'll be able to doing it okay so if you are able to figure it out time in this 24 o'clock
cycle as unshuman says right unshuman might have told you if you have been into is one of
any classes he talks about something called a focused hours do you know this concept of focused
hours focused hours uh so they what he says is what generally happens with the people right
when you're too much busy when you are too much busy uh in your life work life uh even right right
like i it for me uh if i if i have to say so my job plus if you go back sometime back my sister's
marriage right i had family when they have to take care of shopping and things supporting parents
that one family support then preparation for class then taking class so i had four five items going
on in my day life these are the things that i can mention in class so i'm mentioning them
but there were few more things add on so but if you see how i'm able to manage all of these things
is that i i will leverage this one something called focus task technique now focus hours is
let's say i say that from seven to seven a.m to nine a.m nine a.m i'll do for surely focus on
something one activity maybe it is my family time or it's a preparation time or it's taking class
or job time anything i'll surely during this moment of time i have completed that like in
your office you have meetings right which are scheduled in your calendar and you are supposed
to take that you cannot say that i'll sometimes you can say that when you're a really high head
position that can remove this meeting to other time but this is fixed so prepare your google
calendar such a way that you are able to take this and this thing not only will help you for
this next six months of preparation after cracking job but will help you in future also because i've
used family also here because how do you manage that time the better you manage your 24 hour
talk cycle the better more happier and driven you will be okay so when i say for the and even i
my focus stars are divided into something called as promodoro techniques so have you heard this
promodoro like i use 45 hour promodoro technique like yeah i use 45 hours because initially i
started with 15 30 and now my strength goes for 45 minutes i can focus on things for up to 45
minutes not more than that it's it's really difficult to focus for 45 minutes continuously
on one thing but i use this to push my productivity
like i push my productivity for 45 minutes then i relax for 15 minutes
then again i move it okay so that we will be able to complete our task in this 45 minutes focus like
so this is how my things works i can talk about you but when it comes to people who are following
agile i would say that hey take up the work which you have it if there is something add up add those
story points and deal with it because you're not supposed to work because i've told you it doesn't
matter you're putting extra hours 16 20 hours or 23 hours also working doesn't matter
you add only 100 rupees you'll distribute in the whole day there are no extra money any manager
is writing this is applicable for even if you're working google or any company say so okay uh that's
a thing guys so there's a theme of working extras like doesn't matter because if you see most of
the companies are based out of europe and us the people leave like as soon as the time clicks
they leave the office and they go and they enjoy their life but for us
indians indians works comparatively more than what around the globe people work because their
way of looking at life is different our way of looking at life is different too much hardworking
people are japanese in nature japanese continuously can stretch it even they sleep
it in office they don't have uh like kitchens in their home uh like they eat outside in the
restaurants uh japanese culture is completely different like uh post uh like this one right
world war their culture changed it completely if you see them now they are struggling to maintain
this they pay people like if they have planned kids family planning if they do family planning
they government pays the money to them for taking care of them kids like it's it's really uh that
culture is different if you go for country by country the cultures are different so you can
take leverage of those cultures okay like you really like to work go to japan like they will
pay you good also as per your work if you want to enjoy it manage thing go for europe or us based
companies they have their own uh cultural policies you can check them uh they leave after the bosses
like yeah it's it's everything every company will have their own culture guys so but i hope
you got the gist of it that you have to figure it out the time and use focused hours such that
you leverage all the learnings uh and if you need my time right in anywhere i'll try to help you out
but i'll make sure that doom inform me such that i'll you know i have to manage that time also
right my time then i'll try to focus with you so that's what i'm talking about like if you are
able to put efforts i'll also try to give my add-on points okay let's say this is class 21
okay so hello guys then we'll uh yeah yeah i'll i'll try to connect on some time on sunday
if possible okay if things are clear we have discussed good enough things
yeah great yes good night take care guys see you on the next class bye good night guys
okay i've stopped screen sharing in the session guys see you on thursday
you